<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <title>
        
        Alexander Soto</title>
        <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom&#43;xml" /><link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/"/>
    <updated>2019-01-09T14:01:28-05:00</updated>
    <author>
            <name>Alexander Soto</name>
            
                <email>alexander.soto@@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
    <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/</id>
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Review]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/review/2019-01-08/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/review/2019-01-08/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-09T09:49:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Daily Review for 2019-01-08</blockquote>

<p>Daily report: <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue]</span></span></p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>TODO</th>
<th>Headline</th>
<th>Time</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td><strong>Total time</strong></td>
<td><strong>5:37</strong></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Meditation</td>
<td>0:14</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Tea Ceremony</td>
<td>0:03</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Journal writing</td>
<td>0:13</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Review agenda, calendar, goals, habits and brain dump</td>
<td>0:07</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Shower</td>
<td>0:14</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Breakfast</td>
<td>0:25</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Create a study plan for CS5002</td>
<td>1:41</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Lunch</td>
<td>0:41</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Recovery Block</td>
<td>1:07</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Admin Block</td>
<td>0:45</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>Create functional space for tomorrow</td>
<td>0:07</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="create-a-study-plan-for-cs5002"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Create a study plan for CS5002</h2>

<ul>
<li>State &ldquo;DONE&rdquo;       from &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 16:13] </span></span> <br />
Created preliminary schedule</li>
</ul>

<!--listend-->

<ul>
<li>State &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       from &ldquo;TODO&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 11:32]</span></span></li>
</ul>

<!--listend-->

<ul>
<li>Lunch</li>
<li>State &ldquo;TODO&rdquo;       from              <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 11:19]</span></span></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="lunch"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Lunch</h2>

<ul>
<li>State &ldquo;DONE&rdquo;       from &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 13:01]</span></span></li>
<li>State &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       from &ldquo;TODO&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 12:20]</span></span></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="recovery-block"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Recovery Block</h2>

<ul>
<li>State &ldquo;DONE&rdquo;       from &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 17:48]</span></span></li>
<li>State &ldquo;NEXT&rdquo;       from &ldquo;TODO&rdquo;       <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-08 Tue 16:41]</span></span></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accountability]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/accountability/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/accountability/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I was hospitalized for close to two years, the first trip that I made to society was to visit Northeastern University in one of their college tours for prospective students. At the time when I was hospitalized, I was learning Python, and I didn&rsquo;t have reliable access to a computer. In times I didn&rsquo;t have access to a computer, I printed pages from a PDF and took notes on scratch paper that nurses gave me.</p>

<p>I feel immense pride to say years later I was accepted to Northeastern University. I&rsquo;m honored to be the first in my family to be admitted to graduate school. I&rsquo;m a neurodivergent, person of color, Latino pursuing my master&rsquo;s degree in Computer Science. With all that being said I have not done well in my graduate classes. I was unaware of the level of rigor required for the program while also working full-time as a high school teacher compounded with life&rsquo;s challenge&rsquo;s and my own habits, emotions and insecurities.</p>

<p>In this website, I will document my learning path and my process to hold myself accountable for reaching my goal of attaining my master&rsquo;s degree in Computer Science.</p>

<ul>
<li>In the <a href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/now/">Now section</a> you can see my objectives for today, this week, month and year.</li>
</ul>

<!--listend-->

<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/review/">Review section</a> consists of a daily and weekly review, a micro-level look at my day including time stamps and a table with a summary of time spent on a given task.</li>
</ul>

<!--listend-->

<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/courses/">Courses section</a> will contain courses that I am currently taking or have in the past with links to notes taken on the topics presented in the class.</li>
</ul>

<!--listend-->

<ul>
<li>The <a href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/notes">Notes section</a> consists of my notes taken about a subject matter. The notes will be used to create lessons to be made accessible to a broader audience.</li>
</ul>

<p>If you have any comments or suggestions, please feel free to contact me.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Daily Review]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/review/2019-01-07/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/review/2019-01-07/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-08T20:39:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>Daily Review for 2019-01-07</blockquote>

<p>Daily report: <span class="timestamp-wrapper"><span class="timestamp">[2019-01-07 Mon]</span></span></p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th>File</th>
<th>TODO</th>
<th>Headline</th>
<th>Time</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td></td>
<td>ALL</td>
<td><strong>Total time</strong></td>
<td><strong>6:59</strong></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>gtd.org</td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>File time</strong></td>
<td><strong>1:24</strong></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>Rituals</td>
<td>1:24</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;Morning Ritual</td>
<td>1:24</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Meditation</td>
<td>0:16</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Tea Ceremony</td>
<td>0:15</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Journal writing</td>
<td>0:09</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Review agenda, calendar, goals, habits and brain dump</td>
<td>0:13</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Shower</td>
<td>0:16</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td></td>
<td>&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;&ensp;Breakfast</td>
<td>0:15</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td>done.org</td>
<td></td>
<td><strong>File time</strong></td>
<td><strong>5:35</strong></td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Write &ldquo;accountability&rdquo; blog post</td>
<td>1:26</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Reviewing email</td>
<td>0:29</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Errands</td>
<td>2:12</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Swimming at the YMCA</td>
<td>0:52</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Configuring website</td>
<td>0:07</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td></td>
<td>DONE</td>
<td>Late Lunch</td>
<td>0:29</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<h2 id="rise-up-rise-up-good-morning"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Rise up! Rise up! Good morning</h2>

<h2 id="meditation"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Meditation</h2>

<p>Completed 15min Headspace meditation
Thoughts: As the first task in the morning, I am dehydrated. Recommended to hydrate first thing in the morning.</p>

<h2 id="completed-task-tea-ceremony"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Completed Task: Tea Ceremony</h2>

<p>Completed making first cup of tea in the morning.
Thoughts: Start making tea when I begin doing my meditation, by the time I finish meditation my tea will be complete and I can begin doing journal writing with little to no downtime.</p>

<h2 id="journal-writing"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Journal writing</h2>

<p>Completed journal writing. Started while doing boiling tea.</p>

<h2 id="review-agenda-calendar-goals-habits-and-brain-dump"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Review agenda, calendar, goals, habits and brain dump</h2>

<h2 id="shower"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Shower</h2>

<h2 id="breakfast"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Breakfast</h2>

<h2 id="reviewing-email"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Reviewing email</h2>

<h2 id="draft-of-accountability-blog-post"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Draft of &lsquo;Accountability&rsquo; blog post</h2>

<h2 id="write-accountability-blog-post"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Write &ldquo;accountability&rdquo; blog post</h2>

<h2 id="configuring-website"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Configuring website</h2>

<p>Setup Review section to include clocktable summary and timestamps of completed tasks for the day</p>

<h2 id="errands"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Errands</h2>

<h2 id="swimming-at-the-ymca"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Swimming at the YMCA</h2>

<h2 id="late-lunch"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Late Lunch</h2>

<h2 id="task-admin-block"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Task: Admin Block</h2>

<p>Started at 09:31 PM</p>

<p>Purpose: Reviewing captured tasks and setting up tasks for the next day</p>

<h2 id="increase-font-size-in-emacs"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Increase font-size in emacs</h2>

<p>Completed at 09:34 PM</p>

<p>Notes: (set-face-attribute &lsquo;default nil :height 130)</p>

<h2 id="change-names-of-journal-entry-that-has-starting-task-to-task-and-completed-task-to-completed"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Change names of journal entry that has &lsquo;Starting Task&rsquo; to &lsquo;Task&rsquo; and &lsquo;Completed Task&rsquo; to &lsquo;Completed&rsquo;</h2>

<p>Completed at 10:30 PM</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<h2 id="create-function-that-generates-the-properties-needed-for-hugo-and-place-it-underneat-the-current-day-s-datetree"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Create function that generates the properties needed for hugo and place it underneat the current day&rsquo;s datetree</h2>

<p>Completed at 10:31 PM</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<h2 id="create-functional-space-for-tomorrow"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Create functional space for tomorrow</h2>

<p>Completed at 10:33 PM</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<h2 id="take-medication"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Take Medication</h2>

<p>Completed at 10:35 PM</p>

<p>Notes:</p>

<h2 id="admin-block"><span class="org-todo done DONE">DONE</span> Admin Block</h2>

<p>Completed at 10:43 PM</p>

<p>Notes:</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Graduate School]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/graduate-school/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/graduate-school/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-04T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m a graduate student at Northeastern University&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.northeastern.edu/align/academic%5Fprogram/master-of-science-in-computer-science/">ALIGN program</a> pursuing a master&rsquo;s degree in Computer Science. The ALIGN program consists of a series of bridge courses for graduate students who didn&rsquo;t major in Computer Science in their undergraduate studies. Upon completion of the ALIGN program, students begin taking graduate-level classes in computer science.</p>

<p>My interest in attaining a master’s degree in computer science is to link my community experience with technology and leverage this knowledge to contribute to the self-development and self-sufficiency of communities of color, as well as to enhance people’s capacities to solve problems. My long-term goal is to create a workers cooperative of social justice focused technologists, “Technology for Communities,” which specializes in civic technology to assist community organizations by assessing needs, analyzing data and creating solutions. A computer science degree combined with my collective experience as a community organizer will allow me to use technology collaboratively with organizations and individuals to address needs to strengthen communities and amplify our collective voice.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game Over! Continue?]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/game-over-continue/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/game-over-continue/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>From about 2012 to 2014 I was hospitalized due to my mental health. This period was one of the most painful and challenging times for me in my life: being away from friends, family, and society. I was completely excluded from participating in society both physically and mentally, an outcast. I longed to walk in the city, to see my friends and family, to continue my education and to be involved in a community. Upon my release in 2014, I had to restart my life.</p>

<p>I reconnected with friends and started volunteering in different non-profits in the Boston area. My efforts in volunteering eventually lead me to the opportunity of being an AmeriCorps member for United Way. I along with others focused on providing services to residents in Lynn, MA. In my year of service, I served at a high school: supporting students and teachers, creating an afterschool program, being a positive role model and providing support and services to the community. Around the same period, I found out about Resilient Coders. I decided to volunteer in their afterschool program that teaches youth from communities in the Boston area how to code. Fast forward to the present, and I have worked for two years as a technology teacher at a high school in Boston and was accepted into Northeastern&rsquo;s Master&rsquo;s program in computer science.</p>

<p>As a Latino, activist, mental health advocate and technologist, I have learned you must have a systematic understanding of problems and issues that affect organizations, communities, and individuals, to leverage technology as a tool for social change. I am deeply passionate about exploring the use of technology to address the lack of access and inequity in education, health, and unemployment in communities of color.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Humble Beginnings]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/humble-beginnings/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/humble-beginnings/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My beginnings with technology start in early childhood. During the weekends I visited my father and spent most of the time with my brother Robinson. Robinson, an electrical engineer from the Dominican Republic, was my mentor and role-model. When I visited during the weekend, I would find my brother taking apart and repairing different devices. I looked forward to spending time with him, and I would ask questions about technology, such as &ldquo;What is RAM?&rdquo;, &ldquo;What are the differences between AMD and Intel?&rdquo;. As a child, exposure to my brother&rsquo;s work was a valuable resource that expanded my knowledge, sparked my curiosity and interest in technology. As my skills developed, I later assisted my brother in disassembling computers, running diagnostics, installing and upgrading software.</p>

<p>I then attended Middle School, and a science professor was discarding a computer. I seized this opportunity and asked if I could have it, the professor donated the desktop to me. This was my first computer. I carried the large desktop up a hill and walked several blocks to my house. I troubleshot the desktop and identified the power supply wasn&rsquo;t working. I swapped the power supply from an abandoned computer, and voila, I became the proud owner of a Pentium II 233 MHz Desktop Computer.</p>

<p>Through this computer and my 56K modem, I had the world&rsquo;s knowledge at my fingertips. My mind was free to explore my interests unhindered from physical and economic barriers. Having a computer enabled me to excel in my studies compared to my peers who didn’t have access to one. Around the same time, I entered a summer program for Middle School students to take advanced classes and prepare them for high school level work. One of the mentors in the program offered to buy a book from a Barnes and Nobles bookstore. As the years progressed, I learned more about computers, increased my knowledge of technology and about the world.</p>

<p>From my experience, having access to technology or resources,  advanced my learning potential. By the time I entered high school, the skills I had gained proved to be invaluable. I credit having access to a computer at a young age and having supportive mentors in shaping my path on being a self-learner. After graduating high school, I entered college to understand the problems that impact my communities, and I majored in Political Science with minors in Philosophy and Latin American Studies.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
            <link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/hello-world/"/>
            <id>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/hello-world/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published>
            <updated>2019-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years after many conversations with friends about niche topics, staying up late at night pondering life on the verge of an existential crisis, we have arrived here… a blog in 2019? <em><span class="underline">Bueno, mejor que nada…</span></em> This post is titled <span class="underline"><em>&lsquo;Hello World&rsquo;</em>,</span> it symbolizes the first step we take to attempt to communicate with someone or something else while being simultaneously born into a new digital world of our creation.</p>

<p>I want you to step into my world and I’ll take you with me on this journey of pursuing my master’s degree in Computer Science. I see Computer Science as attaining a new ability to be able to see the world through a computational lens, the opportunity to creatively solve problems and to contribute, create and share knowledge with others.</p>

<p>This blog, this world that’s being created will serve as a repository about what I’m currently learning. I intend to share what I’ve learned with others by creating content that’s accessible to a wider audience. As someone who in the past has been deeply involved with community-building as a former community organizer, teacher, and mentor, <strong>I seek to bridge technology and social justice.</strong> I expect this journey to be filled with moments of joy, tears, and frustration… <strong>Pa’lante!</strong></p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
