<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Soto | Bridging Social Justice and Technology</title>
    <link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Soto | Bridging Social Justice and Technology</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 10:35:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/posts/humble-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 10:35:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/posts/humble-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>beginnings with technology starts in early childhood. During the weekends I visited my father and spent most of the time with my brother Robinson. Robinson, an electrical engineer from Dominican Republic, was my mentor and role-model. When I visited during the weekend I would find my brother taking apart and repairing different devices. I looked forward to spending time with him and I would ask questions about technology, such as &amp;ldquo;What is RAM?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Humble Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/humble-beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/humble-beginnings/</guid>
      <description>My beginnings with technology starts in early childhood. During the weekends I visited my father and spent most of the time with my brother Robinson. Robinson, an electrical engineer from Dominican Republic, was my mentor and role-model. When I visited during the weekend I would find my brother taking apart and repairing different devices. I looked forward to spending time with him and I would ask questions about technology, such as &amp;ldquo;What is RAM?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Starting Graduate School</title>
      <link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/starting-graduate-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/blog/starting-graduate-school/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m currently a graduate student at Northeastern University and I&amp;rsquo;m part of the ALIGN program pursuing a master&amp;rsquo;s degree in Computer Science. The ALIGN program are a series of bridge courses for graduate students that didn&amp;rsquo;t major in Computer Science in their undergraduate studies. Upon completion of the ALIGN program students begin taking graduate level classes in computer science. I&amp;rsquo;m currently taking my first ALIGN course, CS5001 or &amp;ldquo;fundies&amp;rdquo; as it&amp;rsquo;s called at Northeastern University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>