<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hyperbole on Alex&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/hyperbole/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hyperbole on Alex&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/hyperbole/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Buttons</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1727-buttons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1727-buttons/</guid>
      <description>Buttons and Smart Keys  Each button performs a specific action, linking to a file, executing a shell command.
 Explicit Buttons accessible from within a single document;
 Global Buttons accessible anywhere within a user&amp;rsquo;s network of documents;
 Implicit Buttons buttons created and managed by other programs or embedded within the structure of a document, accessible from within a single document. Hyperbole recognizes implicit buttons by contextual patterns given in their type specifications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HyControl</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1723-hycontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1723-hycontrol/</guid>
      <description> An Emacs Window and frame management system. You can interactively adjust layout of windows and frames to the pixel level and also lay out large grids of windows.
Hycontrol is binded to C-c \
Related  ยง2019-12-25-1727 buttons ยง2019-12-24-1215 hyperbole ยง2019-12-25-1723 hycontrol  External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbole use cases</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1732-hyperbole-use-cases/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1732-hyperbole-use-cases/</guid>
      <description>Typical Hyperbole applications include:
Personal Information Management Overlapping link paths provide a variety of views into an information space. A single key press activates buttons regardless of their types, making navigation easy.
A search facility locates buttons in context and permits quick selection.
Documentation Browsing Embedding cross-references in a favorite documentation format.
Addition of a point-and-click interface to existing documentation.
Linkage of code and design documents. Jumping to the definition of an identifier from its use within code or its reference within documentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbole</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-1215-hyperbole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-1215-hyperbole/</guid>
      <description>Hyperbole Hyperbole is an efficient, programmable hypertextual information management system.
Hyperbole does not enforce any specific information management model rather allows you to organize information how you see fit.
Includes:
 Hypertextual buttons Hierarchical, record based contact maanger rapid window and frame control system multi-level auto-numbered outliner Hypertext buttons can be embedded within files and other types. Offers Keyboard and mouse-based control of information with multiple windows Has point and click access to URLS, manuals archives etc  Hyperbole consists of five parts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbole</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-1215-hyperbole/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-1215-hyperbole/</guid>
      <description>Hyperbole Hyperbole is an efficient, programmable hypertextual information management system.
Hyperbole does not enforce any specific information management model rather allows you to organize information how you see fit.
Includes:
 Hypertextual buttons Hierarchical, record based contact maanger rapid window and frame control system multi-level auto-numbered outliner Hypertext buttons can be embedded within files and other types. Offers Keyboard and mouse-based control of information with multiple windows Has point and click access to URLS, manuals archives etc  Hyperbole consists of five parts:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>