<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <title>
                Blog on
            
        
        Alexander Soto</title>
        <link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom&#43;xml" /><link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/"/>
    <updated>2019-10-17T10:56:33-04:00</updated>
    <author>
            <name>Alexander Soto</name>
            
                <email>alexander.soto@@gmail.com</email>
            </author>
    <id>https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/</id>
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chunking]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/chunking/"/>
            <id>https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/chunking/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-10-17T10:48:00-04:00</published>
            <updated>2019-10-17T10:48:00-04:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="analogy">Analogy</h2>

<p>Chunking is like working through a jigsaw puzzle. You start with separate pieces, as you work on the puzzle, you create small clusters of pieces or chunks, which contain more meaning and further help you complete the puzzle.</p>

<h2 id="diagram-example">Diagram/Example</h2>




<figure>
    
        <img src="https://www.alexsoto.dev/ox-hugo/chunking_2019-10-17_10-47-48.png"/> </figure>


<h2 id="plain-english">Plain-English</h2>

<p>Chunking is the process that allows us to connect smaller pieces of information into bigger chunks to help us remember.</p>

<h2 id="technical">Technical</h2>

<p>Chunking is a process by which individual pieces of an information set are broken down and then grouped together. A chunk is a collection of basic familiar units that have been grouped together and stored in a person&rsquo;s memory. These chunks are able to be retrieved more easily due to their coherent familiarity.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Learning strategies]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/learning-strategies/"/>
            <id>https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/learning-strategies/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-10-16T10:09:00-04:00</published>
            <updated>2019-10-16T10:09:00-04:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>In my <a href="https://alexsoto.dev/blog/full-stack-open/">previous post</a> I discuss my intention of completing the &ldquo;<a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/">Deep Dive Into Modern Web Development</a>&rdquo; course with the purpose of starting a progressive journey on becoming a software developer. The primary focus of this post is providing a list of resources and learning strategies that are going to be used.</p>

<h2 id="resources">Resources</h2>

<p>Over the years in my experience as being both a teacher and a student I have come across different resources that are related to the field of learning. The learning strategies that I&rsquo;m adopting have been informed by the following sources:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://barbaraoakley.com/books/a-mind-for-numbers/">A Mind For Numbers: How to Excel at Math and Science</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.petercbrown.com/make%5Fit%5Fstick.php">Make It Stick: The Science of Successful Learning</a></li>
<li><a href="https://peakthebook.com/index.html">Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise</a></li>
<li><a href="https://pragprog.com/book/ahptl/pragmatic-thinking-and-learning">Pragmatic Thinking and Learning: Refactor Your Wetware</a></li>
<li>Articles from <a href="https://betterexplained.com/archives/">Better Explained</a></li>
</ul>

<p>This is not an exhaustive list by any measure, there are plenty of other discussions about the topic, doing a search on Google yielded over 8 billion possible results.</p>

<p>The list here represents resources that I turn to when I need a refresher and have found works best for me.</p>

<p>The sources above were chosen for the specific strategies, findings, and thoughts that were presented about learning.</p>

<h2 id="strategies">Strategies</h2>

<p>What follows is a list of learning strategies and concepts that were presented in the books and articles listed above.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://alexsoto.dev/blog/chunking/">Chunking</a></li>
<li>Generation</li>
<li>Elaboration</li>
<li>Retrieval</li>
<li>Reflection</li>
<li>Interleaving</li>
<li>Calibration</li>
<li>Spacing</li>
<li>Deliberate Practice</li>
<li>ADEPT Method</li>
</ul>

<p>In posts to come I will go deeper into each learning strategy and how I&rsquo;m implementing them into an overall learning plan.</p>

<p>This post will be updated periodically with additional resources and strategies.</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Deep Dive Into Modern Web Development]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/full-stack-open/"/>
            <id>https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/full-stack-open/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-10-15T13:45:00-04:00</published>
            <updated>2019-10-15T13:45:00-04:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As part of my learning journey to become a software developer, today I&rsquo;m starting the course &ldquo;<a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en">Deep Dive into Modern Web Development</a>&rdquo;. The course is provided by the <a href="https://courses.helsinki.fi/en/aytkt21009en/130942194">University of Helsinki</a> as part of their <a href="https://www.helsinki.fi/en/open-university/open-university/what-is-the-open-university">Open University</a>.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>This course serves as an introduction to modern web application development with JavaScript. The main focus is on building single page applications with ReactJS that use REST APIs built with Node.js. The course also contains a section on GraphQL, a modern alternative to REST APIs.</p>

<p>The course covers testing, configuration and environment management, and the use of MongoDB for storing the application&rsquo;s data.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>As I work through this course, I will be documenting my progress by creating blog posts and videos that summarize what I&rsquo;ve learned.</p>

<p>In the blog posts that follow I will go over the learning strategies that I&rsquo;ll be incorporating and a deeper look into my learning plan and tools.</p>

<p>The &ldquo;<a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en">Deep Dive into Modern Web Development</a>&rdquo; course consists of 9 separate parts and  4-5 subparts.</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part0">Part 0: Fundamentals of Web Apps</a>

<ul>
<li>a: General Info</li>
<li>b: Fundamentals of Web apps</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part1">Part 1: Introduction to React</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Introduction to React</li>
<li>b: Javascript</li>
<li>c: Component state, event handlers</li>
<li>d: A more complex state, debugging React apps</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part2">Part 2: Communication with server</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Rendering a collection, modules</li>
<li>b: Forms</li>
<li>c: Getting data from server</li>
<li>d: Altering data in server</li>
<li>e: Adding styles to React app</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part3">Part 3: Programming a server with NodeJS and Express</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Node.js and Express</li>
<li>b: Deploying app to internet</li>
<li>c: Saving data to MongoDB</li>
<li>d: Validation and ESLint</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part4">Part 4: Testing Express servers, user administration</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Structure of backend application, introduction to testing</li>
<li>b: Testing the backend</li>
<li>c: User administration</li>
<li>d: Token authentication</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part5">Part 5: Testing React apps, custom hooks</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Login in frontend</li>
<li>b: props.children and proptypes</li>
<li>c: Testing React apps</li>
<li>d: Custom hooks</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part6">Part 6: Statement management with Redux</a>

<ul>
<li>a: Flux-architecture and Redux</li>
<li>b: Many reducers, connect</li>
<li>c: Communicating with server in redux application</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part7">Part 7: React router, styling app with CSS and webpack</a>

<ul>
<li>a: React router</li>
<li>b: More about styles</li>
<li>c: Webpack</li>
<li>d: Class components, E2E-testing</li>
<li>e: Miscellaneous</li>
<li>f: Exercises: extending the bloglist</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="https://fullstackopen.com/en/part8">Part 8: GraphQL</a>

<ul>
<li>a: GraphQL-server</li>
<li>b: React and GraphQL</li>
<li>c: Database and user administration</li>
<li>d: Login and updating the cache</li>
<li>e: Fragments and subscriptions</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
        
        <entry>
            <title type="html"><![CDATA[Hello World]]></title>
            <link href="https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/hello-world/"/>
            <id>https://www.alexsoto.dev/blog/hello-world/</id>
            
                    <author>
                        <name>Alexander Soto</name>
                    </author>
            <published>2019-10-15T08:00:00-04:00</published>
            <updated>2019-10-15T08:00:00-04:00</updated>
            
            
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the years after many conversations with friends about niche topics, staying up late at night pondering life on the verge of an existential crisis, we have arrived here… a blog in 2019? Bueno, mejor que nada… This post is titled ‘Hello World’, it symbolizes the first step we take to attempt to communicate with someone or something else while being simultaneously born into a new digital world of our creation.</p>

<p>I want you to step into my world and I’ll take you with me on this
journey of becoming a software developer. The process of becoming a software developer is like attaining a new ability, to be able to see the world through a computational lens, the opportunity to creatively solve problems and to contribute, create and share knowledge with others.</p>

<p>This blog, this world that’s being created will serve as a repository about what I’m currently learning. I intend to share what I’ve learned with others by creating content that’s accessible to a wider audience. As someone who in the past has been deeply involved with community-building as a former community organizer, teacher, and mentor, I seek to bridge technology and social justice. I expect this journey to be filled with moments of joy, tears, and frustration… Pa’lante!</p>
]]></content>
            
                 
                    
                 
                    
                 
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
