<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Example.com</title>
<description>Example.com</description>
<link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Dec 2018 11:31:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Humble Beginnings</title>
  <description><![CDATA[
<p>
My beginnings with technology starts in early childhood. During the weekends I visited my father and spent most of the time with my brother Robinson. Robinson, an electrical engineer from Dominican Republic, was my mentor and role-model. When I visited during the weekend I would find my brother taking apart and repairing different devices. I looked forward to spending time with him and I would ask questions about technology, such as "What is RAM?", "What are the differences between AMD and Intel?". As a child, exposure to my brother's work was a valuable resource that expanded my knowledge, sparked my curiosity and interest in technology. As my skills developed I later assisted my brother in disassembling computers, running diagnostics, installing and upgrading software.
</p>

<p>
I then attended Middle School and a science professor was discarding a computer. I seized this opportunity and asked if I could have it, the professor donated the computer to me. I became the proud owner of a Pentium II 233 MHz Desktop Computer. This was my first computer. I carried the large desktop up the hill and walked several blocks to my house. I troubleshooted the different parts and identified the power supply wasn't working. I found an extra power supply from an abandoned computer and swapped the power supply. 
</p>

<p>
Through this computer and my 56K modem, I had the world's knowledge at my fingertips. My mind was free to explore my interests unhindered from physical and economic barriers. Having a computer enabled me to excel on my studies compared to my peers who didn’t have access to one. Around the same time, I entered a summer program for Middle School students to take advance classes and prepare them for high school level work. One of the mentors in the program offered to buy a book from a Barnes and Nobles book store. I seized this opportunity and chose the "C++ for Dummies" book (at the time they seemed to be popular and provided comic relief). As the years progressed, I learned more about computers, increased my knowledge of technology and about the world. 
</p>

<p>
From my experience, having access to technology or resources, advanced my learning potential. By the time I entered high school, the skills I gained proved to be invaluable. I credit having access to a computer at a young age and having supportive mentors to shaping my path on being a self-learner. After graduating high school, I entered college to understand the problems that impact my communities and I majored in Political Science with minors in Philosophy and Latin American Studies.
</p>
]]></description>
  <link>https://dynamicmetaflow.github.io/humble_beginings.html</link>
  <pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2018 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
