<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pkm on Alex&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/pkm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pkm on Alex&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/pkm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>From fragmented notes to structured</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1725-from-fragmented-notes-to-structured/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1725-from-fragmented-notes-to-structured/</guid>
      <description>I create notes primarily in two ways.
 Using an org-capture template that captures the note as a subheading and gets refiled to inbox.org which would then get reviewed and may become a note on my system if it has value.
 I create a new note file skipping going to the inbox.
  Once a note is created and or converted to a file it exists in my Zettelkasten system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on note creation for personal system</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1731-thoughts-on-note-creation-for-personal-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1731-thoughts-on-note-creation-for-personal-system/</guid>
      <description> When notes are created they need to be reviewed, there is no easy way to review a note so I think rather than creating multiple files that may be empty I may initially create the note as a subtree, once it&amp;rsquo;s capture i determine if it&amp;rsquo;s worthwile expanding to when it then becomes a file.
The file that is created should also add the relationship with org-brain
Related External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a second brain</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2008-building-a-second-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2008-building-a-second-brain/</guid>
      <description>  GTD: Capture, track, and spread tasks across projects Progressive Summarizing: Make past research easy to pick up and add value to in small chunks over time P.A.R.A (Projects, Areas, Reference, Archive): Store notes over the long term, in simple categories designed to surface them when most actionable Just-In-Time Project Management: Create the conditions for rapidly executing and delivering projects using existing assets.  Related  ยง2019-12-24-1216 org-mode ยง2019-12-24-1216 zettelkasten ยง2019-12-24-1916 information-management  External Links </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>