<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wagetheft on Alex&#39;s Notes</title>
    <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/wagetheft/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wagetheft on Alex&#39;s Notes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://alexsoto.dev/notes/tags/wagetheft/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>List of workercenters</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1718-list-of-workercenters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1718-list-of-workercenters/</guid>
      <description> List of Workercenters in Massachusetts
Worker Centers
Brazilian Women’s Group Brazilian Worker Center Brockton Workers’ Alliance Centro Comunitario de Trabajadores Chelsea Collaborative Chinese Progressive Association Fuerza Laboral MassCOSH Immigrant Worker Center Matahari Women’s Worker Center Pioneer Valley Workers’ Center Restaurant Opportunities Center (ROC) Boston
Related External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wage Theft Workshop</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1720-wage-theft-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1720-wage-theft-workshop/</guid>
      <description>The focus of this workshop is to show how wage theft occurs in our communities and to provide a social and digital context to understand this process through gamification and using workers&amp;rsquo; stories.
 In a floor or a table a large piece of paper will be the playcenter or the community of focus. Index cards will be labeled with different symbols that represent different forms of communication, places, and workers&amp;rsquo; stories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wage theft application - modularity</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1718-wage-theft-application-modularity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1718-wage-theft-application-modularity/</guid>
      <description> The design of the wagetheft application should be design in a way that it allows modules to be created for it, a module for: location, text messages, phone log, etc
Related External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What are worker centers?</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1738-what-are-worker-centers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-25-1738-what-are-worker-centers/</guid>
      <description>Worker centers are community-based mediating institutions that provide support to and organize among communities of low-wage workers. Most centers focus their work geographically, operating in a particular city or neighborhood.
Worker centers in general have emerged in response to the decline of institutions that historically povided workers with a vehcicle for collective action. Immigrant worker centers have emerged as a consequence of the explosive growth of immigrant communities and the absence of infrastucture to support their needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anderson v. Mt Clemens Pottery</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2005-anderson-v-mt-clemens-pottery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2005-anderson-v-mt-clemens-pottery/</guid>
      <description>In 1946 - U.S Supreme Court Case - Anderson Vs. Mt.Clemens Pottery, enabled workers themselves to be the source of reliable evidence in wage cases.
Testimony must be reasonable for workers to testify about hours worked and pay received. Workers testimony is not sufficient due to faulty memory and inconsistencies.
Mt. Clemens Pottery, &amp;ldquo;sufficient evidence to show the amount and text of [damages] as a matter of just and reasonable inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design of wage theft application</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2034-design-of-wage-theft-application/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2034-design-of-wage-theft-application/</guid>
      <description>The application consists of two parts:
Worker inputting current information  hours worked employer information working with workercenter alert messages  Retrieval of past information/history  phone logs location pictures videos  The first part focuses on the worker registering with a workercenter and maintaining and developing a relationship with them.
The second part focuses on building a log / timeline that can be used in court to to corroborate a workers story.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information in the court system</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2007-information-in-the-court-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2007-information-in-the-court-system/</guid>
      <description>  What location related information must an advocate disclose? How to introduce location records? Whom should an advocate bring into the case to support introducing the evidence. How can we use technology as a tool to increase the capacity of community based organizations to address low-wage worker&amp;rsquo;s issues surrounding wage theft, health/safety and workplace violations?  Related  §2019-12-24-2002 location-history-analyzer §2019-12-24-2005 anderson-v-mt-clemens-pottery  External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location History Analyzer</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2002-location-history-analyzer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2002-location-history-analyzer/</guid>
      <description>The Location History Analyzer uses an android smartphone to turn location history into usable evidence
The community legal services of Philidelphia, with Hack4Impact, created a web based tool to turn cell phone location history into evidence.
Transform raw data to an exhibit that summarizes a person&amp;rsquo;s time on the job.
A worker&amp;rsquo;s schedule can vary and contributes to lack of information to hours worked.
A Cell phone is effectively a tracking device that you have decided to wear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wage Theft - Consequences</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2021-wage-theft-consequences/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2021-wage-theft-consequences/</guid>
      <description> According to a report from the Economic Policy Institute, it&amp;rsquo;s estimated that low-wage workers in the U.S lost more than $50 billion to all forms of wage theft in 2016. The disproportionate share of wage theft victims are people of color, women, immigrants, young-people, workers from modest-income households non-unionized workers, and workers who do not have a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree.
Related  §2019-12-24-2007 information-in-the-court-system §2019-12-24-2005 anderson-v-mt-clemens-pottery §2019-12-24-2014 jornalera §2019-12-24-2011 what-is-wage-theft  External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wage theft and lack of information</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2022-wage-theft-and-lack-of-information/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2022-wage-theft-and-lack-of-information/</guid>
      <description>One of the major sources of problem is: lack of information. If workers do not not know how many hours they worked in a given week, the worker cannot figure out whether they are being paid properly.
If a worker cannot testify in court to approximate hours in a given week, they cannot prove liability or damages. A worker&amp;rsquo;s schedule can vary and contributes to lack of information to hours worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is wage theft?</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2011-what-is-wage-theft/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2011-what-is-wage-theft/</guid>
      <description> Wage theft is the failure to pay workers the full wages to which they are legally entitled. Examples include:
 Minimum wage violations: Paying workers less than the legal minimum wage Overtime violations: Failing to pay nonexempt employees time and a half for hours worked in excess of 40 hours per week Off-the-clock violations: Asking employees to work off the clock before or after their shifts Meal break violations: Denying workers their legal meal breaks Illegal deductions: Taking illegal deductions from wages Tipped minimum wage violations: Confiscating tips from workers, or failing to pay tipped workers the difference between their tips and the legal minimum wage Employee misclassification violations: Misclassifying employees as independent contractors to pay a wage lower than the legal minimum or avoid paying overtime  Related  §2019-12-24-2014 jornalera §2019-12-24-2002 location-history-analyzer §2019-12-24-2007 information-in-the-court-system §2019-12-24-2005 anderson-v-mt-clemens-pottery  External Links </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worker Timeline</title>
      <link>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2034-worker-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://alexsoto.dev/notes/posts/2019-12-24-2034-worker-timeline/</guid>
      <description> There exist different sources of information that can be collected from a phone in order to build/illustrate that narrative that&amp;rsquo;s being created.
 Location history Images Videos  Related External Links </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>